[
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between a debit card and a credit card?",
    "answer": "A debit card is a card that allows its holder to pay for goods and services, make transfers, and withdraw cash from an ATM. It holds the cardholder's personal funds.Credit card - a card enabling the holder to pay for goods and services at the expense of the bank. The money on the card belongs to the bank, and the bank lends it on certain conditions. Interest is accrued on the money spent."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to protect your card from fraudsters?",
    "answer": "If you register on unfamiliar and suspicious sites, applications, we recommend:Never, under any circumstances, disclose your personal information to dubious sites;If strangers call you and introduce themselves as an employee of the bank you are using, never disclose your card data;Please do not fall for such fraudulent actions when you receive SMS-messages about winning money prizes in the competitions in social networks.Fraudsters use the same methods to fraudulently obtain your card information."
  },
  {
    "question": "What to do if I lost my bank card?",
    "answer": "Block the card to keep the money safe.To recover the card, you need to go to the bank where this card was opened initially, and apply for its recovery"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to open a deposit?",
    "answer": "You can open a deposit in two ways:Visiting any of the bank\u2019s branches (have a passport with you) Through the bank\u2019s mobile application"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I open multiple deposits?",
    "answer": "The number of deposits per client is unlimited."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the bank address located?",
    "answer": "Our address is Tashkent city, Amir Temur Avenue, 101"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do I need to get a loan?",
    "answer": "It is important to meet the bank's requirements regarding the borrower's age, length of service, etc. You can get acquainted with the loan conditions on the official website of the Bank of Uzbekistan or call the bank's 24-hour call centre on short code 1180."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I get a loan without having an official job, although I have a stable income and a constant turnover on my card?",
    "answer": "In order to obtain a loan, you need to be officially employed. Depending on the type of loan you choose, you will need to provide a payslip for the last four to six months. An income certificate is not required only if you pledge your car as collateral for a microloan or if you make a 40% deposit for a car loan. "
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it possible to leave a pre-application for a loan in the online form?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can do this at www.guide-me.uz. You can also calculate the approximate amount of the loan using the online calculator."
  },
  {
    "question": "If I buy a car on credit, is insurance included?",
    "answer": "When you take out a loan, you can include the cost of car insurance. If you take out a car loan to buy a locally manufactured car from an official dealer, you will receive an annual insurance policy as a gift."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are annuity and differentiated repayment methods?",
    "answer": "Annuity payments are always the same. This makes it easy to plan your budget. The instalments consist of an unevenly distributed debt and the amount of the overpayment. First the interest is repaid, then the principal.The differentiated repayment system is characterised by the fact that the monthly instalments are initially higher and then lower. This is due to the fact that the amount of the principal debt is spread evenly over the entire duration of the credit and that interest is added to it, the amount of which gradually decreases.The overpayment to the bank will be the same in both cases if the debt is repaid according to the payment schedule."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it possible to buy a car on the secondary market?",
    "answer": "No. At present, car loans are only granted for the purchase of new vehicles."
  },
  {
    "question": "What documents are required to apply for a loan?",
    "answer": "Passport or other identity document of the borrower;Income Certificate from the place of work drawn up in accordance with the established procedure;Documents related to securing loan repayment."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the procedure for applying for an online loan?\t",
    "answer": "An online loan is provided remotely using the installed Our mobile App.Continuous salary and equivalent funds for the last three months shall be credited to the borrower's HUMO plastic card."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I make loan payments without visiting the bank?",
    "answer": "Certainly! Customers can make loan payments as well as monitor the status using the installed  Our mobile App."
  },
  {
    "question": "At what age may people get a loan?",
    "answer": "Loans to individuals are provided to citizens of the Republic of Uzbekistan aged 18 to 65 years old who have the income."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can be an educational loan provided to foreign citizens and stateless persons?",
    "answer": "Educational loans are not available to foreign citizens and stateless persons."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be done to unblock the card? ",
    "answer": "To unblock the card, you must contact the bank branch where the card was opened  with your identity document."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the procedure for enabling SMS notification for the card?",
    "answer": "SMS notification for the Uzcard card can be activated through an ATM. SMS notification for the Humo card is activated through the bank branch where the card was opened."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it possible to order a card online without visiting bank branches?",
    "answer": "You can order all cards in national and foreign currency remotely using any Banking Mobile Apps."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I forgot card PIN?",
    "answer": "If you have forgotten your card PIN, please come with your identity document to the bank where the card was opened."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to block a card (UzCard/HUMO) if it is lost?",
    "answer": "If you the card (UzCard/HUMO) is lost, you can block it yourself using the Milliy Bank App or call (78) 148-00 10 and ask the operators to block the card."
  },
  {
    "question": "What international transfers are available at the NBU?",
    "answer": "Currently, the NBU offers the following international money transfers: Western Union, MoneyGram, KoronaPay, Asia Express, Contact, Unistream, Swift, as well as Sberbank."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Visa Direct?",
    "answer": "Visa Direct is a service for money transfer using the Milliy Mobile App to more than 50 countries of the world, including Visa cards of Uzbekistan banks."
  },
  {
    "question": "What documents are required to receive a remittance?",
    "answer": "identity documentMTCN or the tracking numberfull name of remittercountry of remitterexpected amount of money"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I open a deposit remotely?",
    "answer": "It is possible to remotely open, replenish and independently monitor the deposits using the Mobile App."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can my close relatives replenish my deposits?",
    "answer": "If you want to transfer the right to dispose of your deposit to a third party, you must execute a power of attorney certified through a notary office."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I need to contact the bank to close an online deposit?",
    "answer": "No, you don't. The online deposit can be closed through the app."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is capitalisation?",
    "answer": "Capitalization is the addition of accrued interest to the principal amount of the deposit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Demand Deposits",
    "answer": "This is the deposit with no fixed withdrawal period and the depositor can withdraw the funds at any time."
  }
]
